<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moses Akwa Portfolio on Moses Akwa</title>
    <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moses Akwa Portfolio on Moses Akwa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>project 1: Loan Prediction</title>
      <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Dream Housing Finance company deals in all home loans. The company wants to automate the loan eligibility process (real time) based on customer detail provided while filling online application form. Certain details were provided. To automate this process, they have given a problem to identify the customers segments, those that are eligible for loan amount so that they can specifically target these customers.
From the Exploratory Data Analysis that was performed, I was able to generate insight about the data. The model shows how each features relates to the target. Furthermore, from the evaluation I conducted, it can be seen that of all the models employed for the analysis, Logistic Regression Algorithm(LRA) performed far better(83%) than others. Random Forest Classifier(RFC) did better than Decision Tree Classifier(DTC). Support Vector Machine(SVM) also did bettter than K-Nearest Neighbors(KNN). 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2:Hotel Booking Demand Prediction</title>
      <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>The dataset for this project contains booking information for a City hotel and a Resort hotel.
By utilizing the predictive model for this project, hotels will be able to identify the reasons and proffer answers to these questions. Furthermore, this analysis will help hotels get prepared with adequate and timely arrangements on heavy and low tourist visits period.
Using exploratory data analysis, I was able to visualize the different prospective, which gave me different insights into: Which are the busiest months? How many bookings were cancelled? etc.
From the summary table presented on this project, I observe through using various classification model that Random Forest algorithm was the best algorithm for this project analysis. I also presented that bookings got cancelled 37% of the time. While booking guest checked-in (did not cancel the bookings) almost 63% of the time.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2:Lagos Rent Prediction Web Application</title>
      <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>The data for this project was source from PropertyPro and NigeriaPropertyCentre websites. After webscrapping was performed to generate the required data. We cleaned the data before Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) was further conducted using python plotting libraries like Matplotlib, NumPy, and Pandas.
CatBoost Regressor algorithm was used as the regression model, and the results gotten from the model are:
Learn {R2: 0.68, RMSE: 0.60}
Validation {R2: 0.76, RMSE: 0.49}

With the model concluded, an API was created using FastAPI to allow the software teams integrate the model.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>project 4: Wine Quality Prediction</title>
      <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Each wine in this dataset is given a "quality" score between 3 and 8. It was a team project. After evaluation of the performance of the algorithm and testing with four different classification models deployed for the analysis. The following conclusion was made: Random forest classification gave the best and least RMSE value of 0.62. This means that, averagely, an error of + or - 0.62 could be obtained from our prediction.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mosesjnr.github.io/Moses-Akwa-portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media handles.
   Platform URL     Twitter: https://twitter.com/spymozy   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/moses-akwa   GitHub: https://github.com/mosesjnr   Gmail: Mosesakwajnr@gmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
